Guide to the Douglass Cecil North Papers, 1942-2012 and undated RL.00955
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings Series, 1953-2012 and undated; 6
  - Writings by North, 1953-2012; 4
    - Institutions in the Formation and Expression of Values, 1989 (Box 61)
    - Institutions, Organizations and Market Competition, 1996 (Box 61)
    - Institutions, Transaction Costs, and Economic Growth, 1987 July and undated drafts, 2 folders (Box 61)
    - Institutions, Transaction Costs and Productivity in the Long Run, 1993, 2 folders (Box 61)
    - Institutions, Transaction Costs, and the Rise of Merchant Empires, 1987, 2 folders (Box 61)
    - Institutions and a Transaction Cost Theory of Exchange, 1993 (Box 61)
    - Integrating Transaction Costs into Economic History, undated (Box 62)
    - Integrating Transaction Costs into Economic History, 1986 draft (Box 62)
    - Integrating Transaction Costs into Economic History, 1987 revisions (Box 62)
    - Integrating Institutional Change and Technical Change in Economic History: A Transactions Cost Approach, 1994 (Box 62)
    - International Capital Flows and the Development of the American West, 1956 (Box 62)
    - International Capital Movements in Historical Perspective, 1962 (Box 62)
    - Interview with Gail Fosler, 2010 October 1 (Box 89)
      Draft and correspondence. With alternative title "Where do we go from here".
    - Interview with North at Benzonia, MI home., 2008 July (Box 89)
      Correspondence about interviews.
    - Interviews, 2001 (Box 89)
    - Interviews, 2005-2006 (Box 89)
    - Interviews, 2007-2008 (Box 89)
    - Interviews with San Francisco Chronicle., 2008 (Box 89)
    - In the Shadow of Violence: The Problem of Development for Limited Access Order Societies., 2011 (Box 89)
      Review of the revision of In the Shadow of Violence. Correspondence.
    - Is It Worth Making Sense of Marx? 1985, 2 folders (Box 62)
    - Lafayette College Preface, 1984 (Box 62)
    - Law and Economics in Historical Perspective, 2000 (Box 62)
    - Law, Property Rights, Legal Institutions and the Performance of Economies, 1978 (Box 62)
    - Learning, Institutions, and Economic Performance, 2003-2004, 2 folders (Box 62)
      With Mantzavinos, C. and Shariq, Syed
    - Legal Change in Economic Analysis, undated (Box 62)
      With Drobak, John N.
    - Life Insurance and Investment Banking at the Time of the Armstrong Investigation of 1905-1906, 1954, 2 folders (Box 62)
    - Limited Access Orders: Rethinking the Problems of Development and Violence., 2009 (Box 89)
      With Wallis, John J., Webb, Steven B. and Weingast, Barry R. Paper, correspondence and a referee report.
    - Limited Access Orders in the Developing World., 2007 (Box 89)
      With Wallis, John J., Webb, Steven B. and Weingast, Barry R. World Bank Working Paper.
    - Limited Access Orders – Praetorian States., 2010 (Box 89)
      With Wallis, John J., Webb, Steven B. and Weingast, Barry R. Correspondence pertinent to the paper.
    - Location Theory and Regional Economic Growth, 1955 (Box 62)
    - Marco Institutional, Costo de Transaccion y Crecimiento Economico, 1985 (Box 89)
    - Marine Fuel Tax Refund Study, 1966 (Box 62)
      With Barzel, Yoram and Harder, Virgil.
    - Markets., 2000 (Box 89)
    - Markets and Other Allocation Systems in History..., 1973 and undated, 2 folders (Box 62)
    - Marx, Rostow, and History, undated (Box 62)
    - Measuring the Transaction Sector..., 1984, 1 folders (Box 62)
    - Measuring the Transaction Sector..., 1983-1986, 2-7 of 10 folders (Box 63)
    - Measuring the Transaction Sector..., 1983-1985 and undated, 8-10 of 10 folders (Box 64)
    - Miller Upton Addresss, 2008 (Box 89)
      A talk with Bob Virgil, Emily Chamlee-Wright and an anonymous person. Four drafts and correspondence.
    - The Nature of Rules., 2011 (Box 89)
      With Wallis, John J. Chapter two. Draft and correspondence.
    - The Natural State: The Political Economy of Non-Development, 2005 (Box 64)
      With Wallis, John J. and Weingast, Barry
    - The Natural State or Why Effective Economic Reform is so Difficult., 2000s; Writings Series, 1953-2005 and undated (Box 89)
      Talk outline for Uncertainty conference and a draft.
    - Natural State., 2005 (Box 89)
      With Shirley, M., Wallis, John J. and Weingast, Barry R. Draft and correspondence.
    - The New Economic History after Twenty Years, 1977 (Box 64)
    - A New Economic History for Europe, 1968 (Box 64)
    - The New Economies of Institutions and Organization..., 1986 and undated, 2 folders (Box 64)
    - The New Institutional Economics, 1986 and drafts, 2 folders (Box 64)
    - The New Institutional Economics and Development, 1993 (Box 64)
    - The New Institutional Economics and Economic Development, undated (Box 64)
    - A New Theory of Political Economy., 2005 May 12 (Box 89)
      The First Annual Malthus Lecture. University of Herfordshire. Draft and correspondence.
    - The Next 25 Years of Public Choice, 25th Anniversary Special Issue, 1993 Spring (Box 64)
    - Nobel Prize Lecture. Economic Performance Through Time., 1993 December 9 (Box 89)
      Four drafts, correspondence and press commentaries.
    - A Note on Professor Rostow's "Take-off" into Self-sustained Economic Growth., 1958 (Box 89)
      Draft and reprint of published article.
    - Notes on Institutions and Organizations., 2005 (Box 89)
      With Wallis, John J. and Weingast, Barry R. Two drafts.
    - NW (W) Conversation., 2005 (Box 89)
      With Wallis, John J. and Weingast, Barry R.
    - Ocean Freight Rates and Economic Development 1750 – 1913, 1958; 90; box (Box 89)
    - On Kenneth Binmore's Natural Justice, 2006; 90; box (Box 89)
    - Order, Disorder, and Economic Change, undated (Box 65)
    - Outline of the AEA Talk, 2011 (Box 89)
    - Open Access Politics, 2006 (Box 89)
    - The Origin of Growth in Government in the United States Economy: 1789-1914, undated (Box 65)
    - Pacific Northwest Wheat and American Farm Policy, 1954-1955 (Box 65)
    - Paper for Moscow 2010 Conference (Box 90)
      Drafts and correspondence.
    - Paper for Review of Law and Economics, 2009 (Box 90)
    - Paper for Revue de la Management International, 2005 (Box 90)
    - The Paradox of the West, 1993, 2 folders (Box 65)
    - "The Past and the Future of Economic History", undated talk (Box 46)
    - Planning and the Price System in Regional Economic Growth, undated (Box 65)
    - The Political Economy of Poverty, Equity, and Growth, World Bank Proposal, 1985-1986 (Box 65)
    - Political Economics and Environmental Politics, 1977 (Box 65)
    - Political Structure and Economic Institutions in American Growth, undated (Box 65)
    - Preface to Government an the American Economy from Colonial Times to Present (Box 90)
    - Preface to Government an the American Economy from Colonial Times to Present. ref1405_77c, 2005 (Box 65)
    - Privatization, Incentives, and Economic Performance, 1991 and undated, 2 folders (Box 65)
    - Problems in American History, undated, 3 folders (Box 65)
    - The Process of Economic Change, 1997 and undated, 4 folders (Box 65)
    - Process of Economic Change. DN's new book, 2002 (Box 90)
      Draft for the book Understanding of the Process of Economic Change.
    - Prologue to the Frontiers of New Institutional Economics, 1997 (Box 65)
    - Quantitative Research in American Economic History, 1963 (Box 90)
    - A Recommendation on How to Intelligently Approach Emerging Problems in Intellectual Property Systems, 2009 (Box 90)
    - Recorded Papers, Lectures, etc. for D. North Material sent to Duke University, 2000 February (Box 90)
    - Reflections on Economics and Cognitive Science: Some Provisional Thoughts, undated (Box 66)
    - Regional Specialization and Economic Growth in the United States in the Nineteenth Century., 1960s (Box 90)
    - A Reply: Exports and Regional Economic Growth by Chanels, Tiebout, 1956 (Box 66)
    - Reply to the First Economic Revolution as Fiction, by Anne Mayhew, 1982 (Box 90)
      With Anne Mayhew's article, responding to earlier D. North's contribution.
    - Restructuring Political Theory, 2004-2005 (Box 90)
    - Review of Boserup, Population and Technological Change: A Study in Long-Term Trends, 1979 (Box 66)
    - Review of Witold Kula, Measures and Men, 1986 (Box 66)
    - Rise and Fall of the Manorial System, 1971 (Box 90)
    - The Rise of the Western World, 1995 and undated, Approx. 1995 (Box 90)
    - The Rise of the Western World, 1995 and undated, 2 folders (Box 66)
    - The Role of Government in the History of the American Economy, 1968 (Box 90)
    - The Role of Institutions in the Revival of Trade: The Law Merchant, Private Judges, and the Champagne Fairs, 1990 (Box 66)
      With Milgrom, Paul and Weingast, Barry
    - The Role of Institutions for American Indian Economies in the United States and Canada. A PERC Colloquium., 2005 (Box 90)
    - The Role of Transportation in the Economic Development of North America, 1965 (Box 90)
    - Shadow of Violence, 2010 (Box 90)
    - Shared Mental Models: Ideologies and Institutions, undated (Box 66)
      With Denzau, Arthur T.
    - "Shared Mental Models", undated, 46 (Box 46)
    - A Selective Bibliography in American Economic History: Part I, Part II. 1980S (Box 66)
    - Should Transactions Costs be Subtracted from Gross National Product? 1988 (Box 66)
    - Self Determination – the Other Path for Native Americans. Introduction to the book by D. North., 2005 (Box 90)
    - Seigle Hall Dedication. A Talk., 2008 (Box 90)
    - Some Issues in Modeling Economic Change, undated (Box 66)
    - Some Fundamental Puzzles in Economic History/Development, undated, 2 folders (Box 66)
    - Some Theoretical Issues in Regional Economic Growth, 1960s (Box 66)
    - Some Recent Views of the Large Corporation, 1950 (Box 90)
    - Sources of Productivity Change in Ocean Shipping, 1600-185, 1968 (Box 66)
    - The State of Economic History, 1965 (Box 66)
    - Structure and Performance: The Task of Economic History, 1978 (Box 90)
    - The Theory of Double Balance or Why Economic Openness Requires Political Openness and Vice-Versa, With Applications to China's Future and to 17th Century England., 2006 (Box 90)
    - A Theory of Institutional Change and the Economic History of the Western World, 1981 and 1989, 2 folders (Box 67)
    - Third Party Enforcement of Norms and Contracts, 1988 (Box 67)
      With Milgrom, Paul B. and Weingast, Barry R.
    - Three Approaches to the Study of Institutions, 1984 (Box 67)
    - Towards a Property Rights Theory of Exploitation, 1982 and undated, 2 folders (Box 67)
      With Levi, Margaret
    - Towards a Theory of Institutional Change, 1991 (Box 67)
    - A Transaction Cost Approach.., undated (Box 67)
    - Transaction Costs in History, 1985, 2 folders (Box 67)
    - Transaction Costs, Institutions, and Economic History, 1984 (Box 67)
    - Transaction Costs, Institutions and Economic Performance, 1991 (Box 67)
    - A Transaction Cost Theory of Exchange, Chapter 4, 1987 (Box 67)
    - A Transaction Cost Theory of Politics, 1990 undated, 2 folders (Box 67)
    - Tribute to Paul Heyne, 2001 (Box 90)
    - Understanding Economic Change and Economic Growth, 2002 (Box 90)
    - Understanding Institutions, 2000 (Box 90)
    - Understanding the Process of Economic Change, 1999 and undated, 3 folders (Box 67)
    - Understanding the Process of Economic Change., Approx. 1998 (Box 90)
      A draft.
    - Understanding the Process of Economic Change, 1999 (Box 90)
    - Understanding the Process of Economic Change, 2005 (Box 90)
      Sample chapter.
    - Understanding the Process of Economic Change., 2003 May 31 (Box 90)
      Lecture given at "Worlds of Capitalism" conference.
    - Understanding the Process of Economic Change, 2005 (Box 66)
      Endorsements, Reviews and Correspondence.
    - The United States Balance of Payments, 1790-1860, 1960 (Box 67)
    - Valor Economico, 2005 April (Box 90)
      Newspaper Interview, Brazil
    - Various essays published electronically, 1997 (Box 67)
    - Violence and Social Orders. Related Correspondence., 2009 (Box 90)
    - Violence and Social Orders. Outline., Approx. 2008 (Box 90)
    - Violence and Social Orders. Relevant Documents., 2008-2011; 3 folders (Box 90)
      Conditions Governing Access
      mixed_materials
    - Violence and Social Orders. A Conceptual Framework for Interpreting Recorded Human History. Whole Draft., 2007 December (Box 90)
    - Violence and Social Orders. A Conceptual Framework for Interpreting Recorded Human History. Chapter Draft., 2008 March (Box 90)
    - Violence and the Rise of Open-Access Orders. With Wallis, John J. and Weingast, Barry R., 2009 (Box 90)
      Article in Journal of Democracy
    - What do we mean by rationality? 1993 (Box 67)
    - What's Missing from Political Economy, 2005 (Box 67)
    - What's Missing from Political Economy, 2005 (Box 90)
      Chapter for the Handbook of Political Economy
    - Where Have We Been and Where are We Going? 1998 (Box 67)
    - Where Have We Been and Where are We Going?, 1997 (Box 90)
    - Why does Rural Poverty Remain an Intractable Problem?, 2005 (Box 90)
      Draft of paper with Thomas George.
    - Worlds of Capitalism (book from the conference). D. North's chapter "Understanding the Process of Economic Change"., 2005 (Box 90)
    - Worlds of Capitalism (book proposal)., 2003 (Box 90)
      With Miller, Max (editor)
    - WSJ Commentary: The Chinese Menu (For Development), 2005 April 7 (Box 89)
    - Comment on Baumol's Productivity Growth, Convergence and Welfare ...' by Baumol. 1987 (Box 67)
  - Writings by Others, 1965-2001 and undated; 5
    Subseries contains files of drafts and published versions of essays, articles, book chapters, and other writings authored by Douglass North's colleagues and collaborators, among which notable figures in economics, political science, and history. In some cases files contain correspondence, notes and other supporting documents. Arranged alphabetically by author.
    - Aberbach, Joel D. The Congressional Committee Intelligence, 1985 Aug. (Box 68)
    - Abramovitz, Moses and David, Paul A. Towards Historically Relevant Parables of Growth, 1971 (Box 68)
    - Achen, Christopher H. Prospective Voting and the Theory, 1989 Aug. 26 (Box 68)
    - Alchian, Armen A. Some Economics of Property Rights, 1965 (Box 68)
    - Alexander, William Paul. The Measurement of American Federalism, 1974 (Box 68)
    - Alford, John R. Personal and Partisan Advantage in U.S. House Elections, 1846-1986, 1987 (Box 68)
    - Alston, Lee J. Farm Foreclosures in the Interwar Period, 1982 (Box 68)
    - Alston, Lee J. Technological Choice and the Organization of Work in Capitalist Firms, 1987 (Box 68)
    - Alston, Lee J, Eggertson, Thrainn and North, Douglass C. Empirical Studies in Institutional Change, 1979-1992 (Box 68)
      Notes, correspondence, and writings.
    - Alston, Lee J. and Ferrie, Joseph P. Resisting the Welfare State: Southern Opposition to the Farm Security Administration, 1984 (Box 68)
    - Alston, Lee J. and Ferrie, Joseph P. The Use of In-Kind Benefits in Agriculture, 1986 Jan. (Box 68)
    - Alston, Lee J. and Gillespie, William Resource Coordination and Transactions Costs: A Framework for Analysing the Firm/Market Boundary, 1985 (Box 68)
    - Alt, Jim. Crude Politics: Oil and Political Economy of Unemployment in Britain and Norway, 1970-1985, Revised 1986 Aug. (Box 68)
    - Alt, James E. It May Be A Good Way to Run An Oil Company, undated (Box 68)
    - Amel, Eric. Bidding Behavior of Investment Bankers, undated (Box 68)
    - Anderson, Gary M. Exploding the Myth of the Gunpowder Revolution, 1984 (Box 69)
    - Anderson, Gary M. and Tollison, Robert. Luddism as Cartel Enforcement, 1984 (Box 69)
    - Anderson, Gary M, Shughart and Tollison. Adam Smith in the Custom House, 1984 - draft (Box 69)
    - Anderson, Terry L. The Economic Growth of Seventeenth-Century New England: A Measurement of Regional Income, 1972 (Box 69)
    - Anderson, Terry L. and Mill, P.J. Assorted Papers, 1984 (Box 69)
    - Anderson, Terry L, Baack, Bennett, Coelho, Philip R.P. et al. Explorations in the New Economic History: Essays in Honor of Douglass C. North, 1980 (Box 69)
    - Arrow, Kenneth J. Gifts and Exchange, 1972 (Box 69)
    - Arrow, Kenneth J. Political and Economic Evaluation of Social Effects and Externalities, 1968 (Box 69)
    - Arthur, Brian W. Self-enforcing Mechanisms in Economics, 1987 (Box 69)
    - Articles, Comments About Prof. North, 2005-2006 (Box 90)
    - Articles on North (W. U.), 1995-2005 (Box 90)
    - ASU's Ostrom Receives Nobel Medal from Sweden's King., 2011 (Box 90)
    - Assessing Productivity Trends - Some Problems, n.d. (Box 69)
    - Aumann, Robert Repeated Games, 1985 (Box 69)
    - Aumann, Robert J. Agreeing to Disagree, 1976 (Box 69)
    - Austen-Smith, David. Endogenous Agenda Formation, 1986 (Box 69)
    - Axelrod, Robert The Emergence of Cooperation Among Egoists, 1981 (Box 69)
    - Axelrod, Robert Modeling the Evolution of Norms, 1985 (Box 69)
    - Baack, Ben Enclosure Moment in England: 15th-18th Centuries, n.d. (Box 69)
    - Baack, Benneth D. and Ray, Edward John The Political Economy of the Origin and Development of the Federal Income Tax, 1984 (Box 69)
    - Baack, Bennett D. and Ray, Edward J. Special Interests and the Adoption of the Income Tax in the United States, 1985 (Box 69)
    - Bach, Stanley. An Introduction to Conference Committee, 1984 (Box 69)
    - Baijent, Nick: Choice of Subsets: Comment..., undated (Box 69)
    - Baijent, Nick: Some Reservations on Strictly Majoritarian Social Choice, undated (Box 69)
    - Baldwin, Robert E. Rent-Seeking and Trade Policy, 1984 (Box 69)
    - Banks, Jeffrey. Monopoly Agenda Control, 1987 (Box 69)
    - Banks, Jeffrey S. and Calvert, Randall L. Communication and Efficiency, 1988 (Box 69)
    - Barro, Robert J. Government Spending, Interest Rates, Prices and Budget Deficits in the UK, 1730-1918, 1985 (Box 69)
    - Baumol, William J. Productivity, Growth, Convergence, and Welfare: What the Long-Run Data Show., 1986 (Box 90)
    - Boyer, Pascal. Religion Explained. The Evolutionary Origins of Religious Thought. Ch. 5: Why gods and spirits matter?, 2001 (Box 90)
    - Boyer, Pascal. Six Problems for an Integrated Social Science: Can There be a Science-Based View of Human Progress?, 2011 (Box 90)
    - Breit, William and Hirsch, Barry T. Lives of the Laureates. (Chapter on North), 2004 (Box 90)
    - Brousseau, Eric and Glachant, Jean-Michel. New Institutional Economics. A Guidebook., 2008 (Box 90)
    - Coase, Ronald H. and Wang, Ning. China at the Death of Mao., 2011 (Box 90)
    - Compton, Ryan A., Johnson, Noel D. and Yamarik, Steven. War! What is it Good for?, 2007 (Box 90)
    - Barzel, Yoram: An Economic Analysis of Slavery, 1977 (Box 69)
    - Engerman, Stanley L. and Sokoloff, Kenneth L. The Evolution of Suffrage Institutions in the New World..., 2000 (Box 90)
    - Eldred v. Ashcroft Case, Correspondence, 2006; 91 (Box 90)
    - Fine, Ben and Milonakis, Dimitris. From Principle of Pricing to Pricing of Principle., 2001 (Box 90)
    - Fogel, Robert. Several Writings., 1993-1998 (Box 90)
    - Barzel, Yoram: Measurement Cost and the Organization of Markets, 1981 (Box 69)
    - Barzel, Yoram: A Positive Theory of Allocating Resources by Voting, 1984 (Box 69)
    - Barzel, Yoram: Transactions Costs: Are They Just Costs? 1984 (Box 69)
    - Barzel, Yoram and Kochin, Lewis. The Problem of Social Cost, 1985 (Box 69)
    - Bates, Robert H. The Agrarian Origins of Mau-Mau, undated (Box 70)
    - Bates, Robert H. and Lien, Donald. On Operations of the International Coffee, 1985 (Box 70)
    - Bates, Robert H. and Lien, Donald. The Problem of United States Entry into the International Coffee Agreement, 1989 (Box 70)
    - Bates, Robert H. and Rogerson, William P. Agriculture in Development, 1980 (Box 70)
    - van Bath, B.H. Slicher. 18th century Agriculture on the Continent of Europe: Evolution or Revolution? 1980 (Box 70)
    - van Bath, B.H. Slicher. Nienwe wegen in de amerikaanse economische en sociale geschiedenes, n.d. (Box 70)
    - Battalio, Raymond and Kagel, John. Structure of Ante-Bellum Southern Agriculture: Southern Carolina, A Case Study, 1968 (Box 70)
    - Bauer, P.T. and Walters, A.A. The State of Economics, 1973 (Box 70)
    - Bean, Richard N. A Prospect for a Dissertation: The British Trans-Atlantic Slave Trade 1650-1775, n.d. (Box 70)
    - Becker, Gary S.: Competition among Pressure Groups for Political Power, 1984 (Box 70)
    - Becker, Gary S.: The Effect of the State on the Family, 1978 (Box 70)
    - Becker, Gary S.: Public Policies, Pressure Groups, and Dead Weight Costs, 1985 (Box 70)
    - Becker, Gary S.: A Theory of Competition among Pressure Groups of Political Influence, 1983 (Box 70)
    - Becker, Gary S. and Barro, Robert J. A Reformulation of the Economic Theory of Fertility, 1986 (Box 70)
    - Becker, Gary S, Murphy, Kevin M. and Tamura, Robert. Human Capital, Fertility, and Economic Growth, 1990 (Box 70)
    - Bell, Frederick W. Mitigating the Tragedy of the Commons, 1986 (Box 70)
    - Bender, Jonathan and Mookherjee, Dilip. Norms, Cooperation, and Third Party Sanctions, 1988 (Box 70)
    - Bender, Jonathan and Mookherjee, Dilip. Institutional Structure and the Logic of Ongoing Collective Action, 1987 (Box 70)
    - Ben-Porath, Yoram. The F-Connection: Families, Friends, and Firms and the Organization of Exchange, 1980 (Box 70)
    - Benham, Lee and Keefer, Philip. How Diverse Organizations Survive, 1985 Oct. 18 (Box 70)
    - Bernholz, Peter. Growth and Government, Economic Growth, and Individual Freedom, 1984 (Box 70)
    - Berg, Joyce E, Dickhart, J, and Senkow, D. Signalling Equilibrium, 1987 (Box 70)
    - Bierstekes, Thomas J. Reducing the Role of the State in the Economy, 1986? (Box 70)
    - Binder, John J. The Sherman Anti-Trust Act and the Railroad Cartels, 1985 (Box 70)
    - Binder, John J. The Sherman Anti-Trust Act and the Railroad Cartels, 1986- draft (Box 70)
    - Binmore, Ken and Samuelson, Larry. Evolutionary Stability in Repeated Games, undated (Box 70)
    - Birnberg, Thomas and Resnick, Stephen. A Model of the Trade and Government Sectors in Colonial Economies, undated (Box 70)
    - Bittlingmayer, George. "The Economics of a Simple Airline Network, 1985 (Box 70)
    - Bliss, Robert R, Jr. and Ronn, Ehud I. Arbitrage-Based Estimation of Non-Stationary Shifts in the Term Structure of Interest Rates, revised 1988 (Box 70)
    - Blum, Ulrich and Dudley, Leonard. The Making of the French Hexagon, undated (Box 70)
    - Bogue, Allan G. To Shape a Western State: Some Dimensions of the Kansas Search for Capital, 1865-1893, 1971 (Box 71)
    - Books, Papers, etc., 2006-2007 (Box 91)
    - Borcherding, Thomas E. The Causes of Government's Growth: An Empirical Survey, 1984 (Box 71)
    - Borcherding, Thomas E. Competition, Exclusion, and the Optimal Supply of Public Goods, undated (Box 71)
    - Borcherding, Thomas E, Bush, Winston and Spann, Robert The Effects on Public Spending of the Divisibility of Public Outputs in Consumption, Bureaucratic Power, and Size of the Tax-sharing Group, undated (Box 71)
    - Bowler, Shaun and Farrell, David M. Voter Choices in Complex Settings: Voter Preferences under STV-PR, undated (Box 71)
    - Boyd, Michael L. The Evolution of Agrarian Institutions: The Case of Medieval and Ottoman Serbia, undated (Box 71)
    - Boyd, Robert and Lorberbaum, Jeffrey. No Pure Strategy is Evolutionarily Stable, 1987 (draft) (Box 71)
    - Boyd, Robert and Richerson, Peter J. The Evolution of Reciprocity in Sizeable Groups, 1987 (draft) (Box 71)
    - Boyer, George R. What Did Unions Do in 19th Century Britain? 1987 (Box 71)